<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="150546" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="TransitTimetables" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Real timetables for public transport — fixed departures, auto-sized fleets and terminus timing points. Works for buses, trams, trains, metros, ferries and planes." />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<LongDescription>
Turn any public-transport line into a scheduled service. Works for every passenger type: buses, trams, trains, metros, ferries and aircraft.

Per line you opt in and set:
- a first departure time and peak / off-peak / night intervals (the peak windows are configurable),
- the mod then DERIVES how many vehicles the line needs to hold that headway, and raises the game's vehicle-count ceiling so the derived fleet is never clamped,
- a terminus stop (timing point) where early vehicles are held to the scheduled departure, and where surplus vehicles retire — after finishing their loop and dropping passengers, not mid-route.

Select any stop to open a printed-timetable departure board for every line that serves it, listed from the first departure of the day. Day-only and night-only lines only show and run the intervals that apply to them, and a night line is scheduled inside the night window.

No timetable set = the line runs exactly like vanilla. Everything is controlled from the line's own info panel plus a floating departures board.

OPTIONAL SETTINGS (all off by default — a plain timetable needs none of them):
- "Realistic travel time" (free): the game's own loop estimate is optimistic (it ignores the time buses lose braking and accelerating at every stop), so posted times drift ahead of reality. Turn this on and the mod measures each line's REAL loop as it runs and posts realistic stop times, so early buses wait at each stop until their true departure. It warms up — for the first day or two it still shows the estimate while it measures, then switches each stop to the measured time.
- "Provision fleet for real travel time" (costs money): also sizes each line's vehicle count to its real loop. A line whose real loop is ~2x the estimate needs about twice the vehicles to hold the same headway. Grow-only and capped.
- "Stop at every stop (even empty ones)" (free): by default a bus skips a stop where nobody boards or alights, so that stop isn't held to schedule; the terminus is now always honoured, and this extends that to every stop. Lines run a little slower.
- "Realistic Trips / slow-time compatibility" (ALPHA): keeps timing correct if you run a mod that lengthens the in-game day (Time2Work / Realistic Trips). Leave off otherwise.

Recommended: for accurate timetables at no cost, turn on "Realistic travel time" and leave the rest off; add "Provision fleet" only if you want the mod to also buy the buses that headway really needs.

KNOWN ISSUES:
- "Vehicles no longer un-bunch after removing the mod." The mod writes two values into a line's save data — an "unbunching factor" (an early pre-v0.2.3 build), and a "vehicle interval" it uses to size the fleet. If you remove or disable the mod WITHOUT first switching a line's timetable off, those values can stay frozen in the save (the base game never resets them), so vehicles leave a stop immediately without spacing out. FIXED as of v0.3.2.2: the mod now repairs both automatically on load, for every line, and safely — the vehicle interval is rebuilt from the line's own settings, so a count you set by hand with "Assigned Vehicles" is preserved. To repair an affected save: subscribe to v0.3.2.2 (or newer), load your city, then save. Normal unbunching returns, and you can keep or remove the mod afterwards.

Source (open source, MIT): https://github.com/AmicusDeus/TransitTimetables

Made with Claude Code's Opus 4.8 and Fable 5 models.
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="0.3.2.2" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.6.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="" />
	<!--Required DLC, can be set multiple times. Supported values are "Landmark Buildings", "San Fransisco Set", "Beach Properties", "Urban Promenades", "Modern Architecture"-->
	<RequiredDLC Value="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
v0.3.2.2 — Complete the after-removal unbunching repair (fleet-interval residue)

- FIX: v0.3.2 repaired only one of two things the mod leaves in a save. To size a line's fleet the mod writes a "vehicle interval" value into the line's data; if you remove/disable the mod WITHOUT first switching a line's timetable off, that value stays frozen in the save and the game keeps reading it, making it think buses are spaced far tighter than they are — which collapses the anti-bunching hold and a vehicle leaves the stop immediately no matter how close the next one is. This version clears that leftover automatically on load, for every line, and does it safely: it rebuilds the value from the line's own settings, so a vehicle count you set by hand with the "Assigned Vehicles" slider is preserved. To repair an affected save: subscribe, load your city, then save (you can remove the mod afterwards). No-op on a healthy save.

v0.3.2 — Auto-repair for the old unbunching-factor residue

- FIX: an early version of this mod (before v0.2.3) set a line's "unbunching factor" to 0 on the lines it managed, to stop buses idling mid-route. That value is saved with your city and the base game never resets it, so on an affected save — especially after removing the mod — vehicles could leave a stop immediately no matter how close the next one is. Current versions already repaired this while installed, but only on lines you still had timetabled. This version repairs EVERY line automatically on load: any line whose unbunching factor is 0 is reset to the game's default. So on an affected save just subscribe, load your city and save, and normal unbunching is restored (even for lines you no longer timetable). It only touches lines stuck at 0, so a healthy save is unaffected.

v0.3.1 — Buses now always stop at the terminus (and optionally at every stop)

- FIX: a bus could SKIP a stop where nobody was boarding or alighting (base-game behaviour — the bus only slows and rolls through, never pulling in). A skipped stop is never held to its scheduled departure, so the bus ran ahead of its timetable — and this could even happen at the TERMINUS, skipping the scheduled wait that anchors the whole line. Timetabled lines now ALWAYS force a stop at the terminus, so the schedule is honoured. (Reported by a community member — thank you.)

- NEW: "Stop at every stop (even empty ones)" setting, OFF by default. Extends the forced stop to every stop on a timetabled line, so every posted departure is honoured — at the cost of a short dwell at each empty stop, which makes lines run a little slower. Buses and other road vehicles only; trains, trams, ships and planes already stop at every station in the base game.

v0.3.0 (alpha) — Realistic travel time + per-line custom peak windows

- NEW (ALPHA): "Realistic travel time". Cities: Skylines II's own estimate of how long a line takes is optimistic — it ignores the time buses lose accelerating and braking at every stop, so timetabled lines quietly run a longer effective headway than you set, and the vanilla "vehicles needed" count is too low. The mod now measures each line's REAL loop as it runs and corrects for it. Two new settings, BOTH OFF BY DEFAULT:
  • "Realistic travel time (correct posted times)" — posts realistic stop times so the departures board matches what the buses actually do. Free; it only makes the clock honest.
  • "Provision fleet for real travel time (costs money)" — also sizes each line's vehicle count to its real loop. This one spends: a line whose real loop is ~2x the estimate needs about twice the vehicles, and twice the upkeep. Grow-only and capped. OFF = your fleets are unchanged and the panel just tells you the real number needed.
  Self-calibrating per line, per city — no setup; a new line uses a stop-density estimate until it has measured itself. Works alongside slow-time mods (measured in sim-frames, so a stretched clock doesn't affect it). ALPHA — please report anything odd.

- NEW: per-line custom peak windows (thanks to community contributor incconutwo). A line can set its own two peak windows and headway — e.g. a school or commuter line that runs frequently only 07:00-09:00 and 16:00-18:00 — overriding the global peak settings, without affecting other lines.

- The "Realistic Trips / slow-time compatibility" setting now defaults OFF (turn it ON only if you run Time2Work / Realistic Trips); the mod logs a note if it detects such a mod while the setting is off.

Earlier: v0.2.83 added station terminus points, per-row "Set as terminus" buttons, and the "Keep achievements enabled" toggle; v0.2.7 fixed the vanilla "Assigned Vehicles" slider; v0.2.3 restored on-time departures.
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link, can be set multiple times. supported types are "discord", "github", "youtube", "twitch", "x", "paypal", "patreon", "buymeacoffee", "kofi", "crowdin", "gitlab", "gofundme"-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/AmicusDeus/TransitTimetables" />
	<!--Supported values Public, Private, Unlisted-->
	<AccessLevel Value="Public" />
</Publish>
